# KristijanPerusko

software engineer

#### **Contact**

347 972 6973 kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

#### Links

Github:// kperusko Bitbucket:// kperusko Linkedin:// kperusko

## Languages

English, Croatian

## **Programming**

Experience using: PHP, JavaScript HTML & CSS

Familiar with: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

## Db

MongoDB, MySQL

## Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

#### Other

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

## **Summary**

I've worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer. I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations, because I find them more challenging and therefore more interesting. This said, I would love to work more with functional programming.

# **Experience**

2008-2014 Novatec "New Technologies"

Team leader | Software engineer

In-house software engineer for my first two years. Became team leader building client's booking system and multiple customer-facing sites. Also served as project leader where I gathered requirements from clients, mentored junior engineers, planned and implemented critical features. My responsibilities included administration and optimization of MongoDB and MySQL DBs and Ubuntu/Debian servers.

2007-2008 **Tempo** 

IT administrator

MongoDB

Responsible for Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

2005-2007 Vlado elektronika

Sofware and electrical QA engineer

Veleuciliste u Rijeci (Rijeka College)

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time by 60%.

## **Education**

2013 **BS of information tehnology** 

Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework

2002 **Electrical engineering** 

ectrical engineering Mate Blazina High Scho

DC servo driver controlled by IR remote

# **Online courses**

M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations

MongoDB

Principles of Reactive Programming Coursera

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

Machine Learning Coursera

Stanford University

Interactive Programming in Python Coursera

Rice University

M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers

MongoDB

MongoDB

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

Startup Engineering Courser

Stanford University